

Bilawal Riaz

Python Developer

Phone: +44 7944324418 Email: inbox@bilawal.net

LinkedIn: /in/bilawalriaz GitHub: /bilawalriaz

Website: <u>hyperflash.uk</u>

Experienced IT professional with a comprehensive background in IT infrastructure, cloud, bioinformatics and Python. Demonstrated success in managing and executing large-scale projects to satisfy business requirements. Pursuing a dynamic role in the IT/Cyber-Security sector to apply my expertise and problem-solving acumen for substantial impact. 'Jack of all trades, master of none... oftentimes better than master of one.'

Skills

I already know

Python 4/5 SQLite3 4/5 Tailwind CSS 3/5 PostgreSQL 2/5 MongoDB 2/5

Firebase 3/5 Supabase 3/5

I want to learn

React.js

I speak

English Native Punjabi/Urdu

Work experience

IT Infrastructure Engineer

dotdigital

- In tristique vulputate augue vel egestas.
- Quisque ac imperdiet tortor, at lacinia ex.
- Duis vel ex hendrerit, commodo odio sed, aliquam enim.
- Ut arcu nulla, tincidunt eget arcu eget, molestie vulputate nisi.
- Nunc malesuada leo et est jaculis facilisis.
- Fusce eu urna ut magna malesuada fringilla.

Technologies: React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Nx, Firebase

September 2022 - now

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process.

Facebook

- Aenean eget ultricies felis. Pellentesque dictum massa ut tellus eleifend, sed posuere massa mattis.
- Ut posuere massa lacus, eleifend molestie tortor auctor vel.
- Sed sed sollicitudin eros, id ultricies mi. Aliquam sodales elit vel ante tempor, non vehicula nibh facilisis.
- Cras feugiat ultricies maximus. Aliquam tristique ex odio, ac semper urna accumsan a.

Technologies: React.js, React Query, Chakra UI, ESLint

Junior front-end developer

September 2016 - April 2019

GitLab

Nulla volutpat justo ante, rhoncus posuere massa egestas in:

- Quisque pellentesque, dolor nec sollicitudin iaculis, sem velit consequat ligula, eget tempus ligula leo et est.
- Maecenas ut elit sit amet nibh maximus condimentum in nec lorem. Pellentesque tincidunt odio vel leo suscipit, in interdum mi gravida.

Donec non vulputate augue 🤓

Technologies: Python, Tailwind CSS, pnpm

Projects

Golden Bulls March 2020 - now

In tristique vulputate augue vel egestas. Quisque ac imperdiet tortor, at lacinia ex. Duis vel ex hendrerit, commodo odio sed, aliquam enim. Ut arcu nulla, tincidunt eget arcu eget, molestie vulputate nisi. Nunc malesuada leo et est iaculis facilisis.

Demo: https://golden-bulls-d73jd7.netlify.app

Repository: https://github.com/mark-freeman/golden-bulls

Technologies: Next.js, SASS, pnpm, ESLint, Prettier

TruQuest

June 2019 - February 2020

Ut ultricies tortor at sodales aliquam. Vivamus metus ante, fringilla nec ligula in, suscipit rhoncus mauris. Praesent hendrerit velit odio, at accumsan urna faucibus convallis. Nunc at massa eget ligula volutpat dictum a sit amet libero. Vestibulum iaculis molestie maximus. In hac habitasse platea dictumst.

Demo: https://tru-quest-ck7ea3.netlify.app

Repository: https://github.com/mark-freeman/tru-quest

Technologies: React.js, Tailwind CSS, NestJS, PostgreSQL

Software Chasers

January 2018 - December 2020

Quisque id consectetur eros. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed eu pulvinar orci. Mauris consequat, est in dignissim varius, neque nisl commodo mauris, id blandit risus justo eu nulla.

Demo: https://software-chasers-e82l8e.netlify.app

Repository: https://github.com/mark-freeman/software-chasers

Technologies: React.js, Chakra UI, TypeScript, Nx, pnpm

Disco Ninjas

May 2016 - July 2018

Praesent eu neque tortor. Vestibulum ac magna nisl. Vivamus massa sem, feugiat in pharetra non, convallis egestas purus. Ut consequat ullamcorper sem, in euismod nibh posuere ut.

Demo: https://disco-ninjas-g321ol.netlify.app

Repository: https://github.com/mark-freeman/disco-ninjas

Technologies: TypeScript, Jest, Firebase

Education

Information Technology

October 2014 - July 2016

Wrocław University of Science and Technology

Master degree. Specialization in software development.

Information Technology

October 2011 - July 2014

Wrocław University of Science and Technology

Bachelor's degree. Specialization in application development.